Budget Rules is a feature in Campaign Manager that helps you manage and optimize your budget.
It can automatically increase your budget during a specific timeframe, or when your campaign hits
a certain performance target.
You can use budget rules to help you keep top performing campaigns running, to prevent budget being
spent on underperforming campaigns.
To reduce time,
spent monitoring and manually adjusting your campaigns and optimize your budget for key events
with personalized recommendations.
There are two types of budget rules.
Scheduled-based rules allow
you to set budgets in advance for special events, such as Prime Day or Halloween or during a date
range of your choice.
For example, during an important shopping event such as Black Friday,
you can set your budget to increase by 50% to help make the most of the anticipated increase in
shoppers.
Performance-based rules will increase your campaign budget when your campaign meets a
certain performance threshold, such as ROAS, click-through rate or conversion rate.
For example,
if you want your budget to increase when your campaign is performing well, you could set your
budget to increase by 20% when your ROAS hits 5.
Make sure to apply budget rules during your
next important event to help make the most of your campaign.
Check out our follow-on video
to find out how to set up a budget rule.